barefoot-books.com 2017-12-21

# Barefoot Books :: Privacy Policy

Barefoot Books Inc’s (“Barefoot Books”) Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the personal information you decide to share, and also help you make informed decisions when using the Barefoot Books web site and services.

By using or accessing the Barefoot Books web site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

## What information is collected

In order to become a member of the Barefoot Books community, a user must first complete the registration process. During registration a user is required to provide their contact information (such as name, e-mail address, and postal address) and additional psychographic data.  Users are also required to provide and verify a valid e-mail address before the account creation process can be completed.

Once established members who have opted in will receive e-mails containing information regarding products, community activity, and directives from Barefoot Books, from time to time. "Opted-in" means the member has approved certain e-mails to be sent to them from Barefoot Books, Inc.

Under rare circumstances Barefoot Books may need to contact specific or all members in order to make an important announcement about the Barefoot Books site or service changes. Members are not able to unsubscribe, or "opt-in/opt-out" of these announcements because they may contain very important information regarding their accounts. Barefoot Books reserves the right to contact members to correct account errors or to supply important information Barefoot Books deems relevant.

### Our Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data we store for each user session that gives you a unique ID number. We use cookies to allow us to personalize your experience on our website and to allow you to move from page to page while staying logged into your account.

### Log Files

We do track certain information such as type of browser and log on time for our own use. We use this information only to track from where our members may be coming and what type of software they are using. We keep this information so we can continuously improve our users' online experience and improve the Barefoot Books website. None of this information can ever be traced back to any specific person and is useful only to Barefoot Book.

### Correction/Updating Personal Information

Barefoot Books users are able to change their personal information at any time through their account on the Barefoot Books website.

### Children

Barefoot Books recognizes that parents, guardians, or other adults often purchase our products for family use, including use by minors. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 for marketing purposes, but because some information is collected electronically, it can appear to be the personal information of the Barefoot Books purchaser of the product, and will be treated as such under this privacy policy. If a child under 13 submits personal information to Barefoot Books and we learn that that personal information is the information of a child under 13, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible.

## When we disclose your information

**Barefoot Books takes your privacy very seriously. Barefoot Books does not share, sell or rent your contact information.   **

However, there are times when it may be advantageous for Barefoot Books to make certain personal information about you available to companies that perform work for Barefoot Books. These companies may help us process information, extend credit, fulfill customer orders, deliver products to you, manage and enhance customer data, provide customer service, or conduct customer research or satisfaction surveys.

Also at times we may be required by law or litigation to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary.

## How we protect your information

Barefoot Books takes precautions — including administrative, technical, and physical measures — to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

Barefoot Books uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on all web pages where personal information is required. To make online purchases from Barefoot Books, you must use an SSL-enabled browser. Doing so protects the confidentiality of your personal and credit card information while it’s transmitted over the Internet.

We encourage you to take precautions to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. Among other things change your passwords often using a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure web browser.

While we use both passwords and usernames to protect information online, we also take steps to protect users' information off-line. All of our users' information is restricted in our offices and only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment and professionally maintained. Please keep in mind that you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information.
